<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Liberal Letters & Code</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-03-04T23:33:48+01:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who is the Mark Cousins of code?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/mark-cousins-code/" />
  <id>/mark-cousins-code</id>
  <published>2015-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When I look to find expertise in a specific discipline I tend to enjoy it far more when learning from someone who possesses a passion and peculiar, fierce human love for the subject matter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be that a teacher, a critic or an artist, it’s just more fun when you’re listening to someone who is slightly nuts about what they’re into. I also tend to trust and return to these rare few when I want to learn more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are equivelents in other crafts - and I do think you can call code a craft, there is an artisinal side to it - but I’m hard pressed to find the same sort of voice in technology, in design or in development in general.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea of what I mean. Here are a few examples from other disciplines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cinema---mark-cousins&quot;&gt;Cinema - Mark Cousins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Cousins is a cinephile of the highest order. He speaks about cinema as if each frame of celluloid is a precious mineral. He makes shapes with his hands and forms his words with the precision of poet. Here he is talking about his &lt;em&gt;‘companion’&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/indtGfuozgc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;literature---michael-silverblatt&quot;&gt;Literature - Michael Silverblatt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to literature, there is no voice I would rather listen to than Michael Silverblatt whose radio show/podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcrw.com/news-culture/shows/bookworm/karl-ove-knausgaard-my-struggle-part-ii&quot;&gt;KCRW’s Bookworm&lt;/a&gt; which is on regular play on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/overcast-podcast-player/id888422857?mt=8&quot;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt;. His cultural insights are often more interesting than whatever the writers he interviews have to say about their own work. Silverblatt also rarely comes off stuffy and is always gracious about the work - since he actually reads all of the books. Skip to 0:25:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wOQxr9SLp0s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;art-history---waldemar-januszczak&quot;&gt;Art History - Waldemar Januszczak&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t much go in for art history but I was turned on to it by a friend who had me watch the incredibly geeky &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CS_HUWs9c8c&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tim’s Vermeer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; documentary. I have heard this Januszczak fellow is fun to listen to. He does seem to possess the same degree of mind-boggling knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xtf7uPF_9rU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these engender a deeper love and understanding about the craft we choose to be a part of. But perhaps it is because programming is a relatively different form. It isn’t art but it is a form of expression however way you look at it. Sure there is such a thing as beautiful code but I think I’m trying to get at how we talk about code and development in general. For example, what I find facinating is how Javascript is constructed and thought about as a tool and lanaguage framework. I’ve only just begun learning but it is what compels me to keep going. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logic structure and systems perhaps doesn’t lend well to flowering descriptions but then again architecture doesn’t seem to suffer for the same. There is more to all this than being a functional way to build things on the web or otherwise and I am surprised at the lack of distinct voices. This is especially true when it comes to the axis of design, technology and society. Perhaps the like heart on &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/&quot;&gt;Dribble&lt;/a&gt; needs to be enhanced somehow or perhaps I just haven’t turned the corner and found them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far the writers and old artisans at &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; have come closest.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mark-cousins-code/&quot;&gt;Who is the Mark Cousins of code?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on March 04, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Gulp.js (updated as I go)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/gulpjs/" />
  <id>/gulpjs</id>
  <published>2015-03-03T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;transitioning-away-from-codekit&quot;&gt;Transitioning away from CodeKit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I can very much attribute to my crossing into design and development is the sheer amount of tools that are readily available to download for free. I intend to share the full details of my setup in another post but my day-to-day workflow consists almost exclusively of tools that I came across for free (Compass for instance which I use to compile my CSS) or tools that came pre-existing with my Mac i.e Terminal. This ostensibly means that a new developer can begin to learn to code for next to nothing. This is wonderful and makes a great case for anyone, anywhere to jsut dive in and begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often than not I have found that initial searches for tools offer paid-for clients that often come equipped with an easy-to-use GUI. These tools are often designed to do a few things reliably and very well. An example of this is the brilliant CodeKit which I have been using solely for live-reload and style injections. Live-reload is where my Chrome browser is asked to auto-refresh any time I make a change to the code. This is incredibly helpful when it comes to editing things like CSS styles, which take up the majority of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, CodeKit does a great job and is well worth paying for. It is also relatively affordable since you get name your price (between $30 - $40) after a 14 day trial. But there are free tools out there that offer similar results. One of which is Gulp.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-gulpjs&quot;&gt;Why Gulp.js?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it is free. When building a startup this is an immeasurably large consideration since it means resources (even $35) can be better used elsewhere. Gulpjs also does a great number of other things to boot. It’s also a Sass compiler and can be used to create a number of functions. but was recommended to me as a way to replace CodeKit when it comes to livereload a YouTube commenter. Suprising, I know. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll let you know how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/gulpjs/&quot;&gt;Using Gulp.js (updated as I go)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on March 03, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[LayerVault conducted an AMA with Matias Duarte]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/ama-duarte/" />
  <id>/ama-duarte</id>
  <published>2015-03-03T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Matias Duarte just concluded an &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.layervault.com/stories/45342-ama-im-matias-duarte-a-vp-of-design-at-google&quot;&gt;AMA with LayerVault.&lt;/a&gt; There were a number of very interesting insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;on-focusing-on-the-problem&quot;&gt;On focusing on the problem:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have a mantra I follow when tackling design projects, which is focus on the problem. Too many times I’ve fallen in love with an idea and wasted a bunch of time. However if you focus on something that’s a problem - something that causes pain or frustration or is an unmet need - you know you’re not just building a fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly interesting was his frustration with the lack of concensus when it comes to iconography and how this affects adversly on usability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consensus-on-iconography&quot;&gt;Consensus on iconography&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve seen usability study after study that shows the glyphs we currently use cause confusion to first time users. The problem is exacerbated by the reality that our users use a mix of platforms during the day. Asking designers to use text is not an option - these common functions can take up too much space and are often hard to label meaningfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;on-his-design-influences&quot;&gt;On his design influences:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I guess personally I’m most comfortable working in the abstract expressionist school. Gorky and Matta are the painters my work is most similar too. Though my figurative influences are heavily pop cultural … maybe cross the above two with Takashi Murakami and Audrey Kawasaki?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a Murakami for reference: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.modearte.com/wp-content/uploads/Takashi-Murakami-ModeArte-Louis-Vuitton.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/80901381@N04/7758832526/&quot; title=&quot;Takashi Murakami floral art&quot;&gt;Takashi Murakami&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/ama-duarte/&quot;&gt;LayerVault conducted an AMA with Matias Duarte&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on March 03, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google are experimenting with :hover highlighting]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/google-highlighting/" />
  <id>/google-highlighting</id>
  <published>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Previously :hover states for search links were the usual underline. If legitimate it’s an interesting experiment to watch  given the bellwether effect Google design currently attracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ef27zOo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/google-highlighting/&quot;&gt;Google are experimenting with :hover highlighting&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A win for digital roles and immigration - from COADEC]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/coadec-immigration/" />
  <id>/coadec-immigration</id>
  <published>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coadec.com/&quot;&gt;COADEC&lt;/a&gt; are a non-profit made up of tech entreprneurs that support and campaign around policy on behalf of the UK’s startup community. I’ve followed their work and have admired their effectiveness. Today comes news of a win on the stagnant immigration front:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some great news for digital startups today as the Migration Advisory Committee (MAC) has recommended to the Home Office that several digital roles should be added to the Shortage Occupation List (SOL). We called for this in our Startup Manifesto, and have been campaigning for this change alongside techUK and Tech London Advocates.  The MAC is the expert body that advises the government on migration issues, and its recommendations are almost always implemented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They recommend that the following roles, for those with over 5 years experience, should be added to the Shortage Occupation List:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Product Manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Scientist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Senior Developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cyber-Security Specialist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coadec.com/some-good-news-on-immigration/&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coadec-immigration/&quot;&gt;A win for digital roles and immigration - from COADEC&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Struggling with a personal response to ISIS]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/isis-museum/" />
  <id>/isis-museum</id>
  <published>2015-02-28T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;For me, writing becomes a process of divining thought patterns. It is almost a kind of striving to settle upon a conscious, cogent and original opinion. Seeking a subjective truth is a deceptively difficult thing to do. So much of what we tend to say about the world can be traced back to heard words and framing found to lay elsewhere. Independent thinking comes down to trusting your own capacity for an original, personal opinion. People are not puppets nor mouthpieces. Nothing comes from adopting an easier path, one of repeating commentary without trusting your own engaged and curious mind. For me, it is worth struggling with ourselves so that an answer has a chance to spring from a place of authenticity and purpose. For me, this is an essential part of offering a responsible perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, just before heading to bed, I came across a post from a friend. The post was a video of ISIS fighters destroying ancient relics that had been housed in Iraq’s Mosul Museum. My initial response would have been similar to most people who had seen the video I imagine; shock, abhorrence, alarm and repulsion. There is violence in this reaction. But it was a violence that feels as if deliberately enticed by what I was watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed.theguardian.com/embed/video/world/video/2015/feb/26/islamic-state-militants-destroy-ancient-iraqi-artefacts-mosul-video&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I haven’t watched the beheading videos released by ISIS. I couldn’t watch the video where Moath al-Kasabeh, the Jordanian pilot was burnt alive. I have seen clips however and I remember noticing the remarkable sophistication of the material, the editing, music and scale of production. They are polished, these videos. Admittedly this is an odd thing to point out but I believe something significant has happened since ISIS has come into power in Syria and Iraq. It is that the language has changed. The channels with which movements like ISIS roll out propaganda have gone beyond the 24 news cycle. These videos are a nightmare cut and packaged for the social stream, made for and of the Internet. We’re now seeing reports of young second generation Muslims leaving parts of the UK and Europe to join ISIS. You can see the compelling aesthetic all over this media campaign and that’s why I’m not surprised. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The violence I felt after watching this video; &lt;em&gt;Bomb them, wipe them out, drone strike them out of existence&lt;/em&gt; might be understandable given the destruction. Ancient statues and headstones smashed and toppled into pieces, scattered history, 3000 year old heritage destroyed, art belonging to all of us. It is all too easy to turn initial reactions like these into justifications for some form of retribution. It is harder to move beyond it toward a rational response. So what to do other than to seek out more knowledge, find opinions that you wouldn’t normally agree with and weigh them up against what you feel instinctively. In the days since, I began thinking about why these videos are released in the first place. Why else but to seduce us into hatred and push us toward conflict and yet another cycle? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend these for further reading: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/27/world/middleeast/historians-pore-over-isis-video-of-smashed-statues-for-clues-to-whats-been-lost.html&quot;&gt;Historians Pore Over ISIS Video of Smashed Statues for Clues to What’s Been Lost - Robert Mackey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mondoweiss.net/2015/02/about-when-isis&quot;&gt;What we talk about when we talk about ISIS - Eamon Murphy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/2015/02/sacrificial-books-mosul-150227060556341.html&quot;&gt;ISIL torches Iraqi history in Mosul - Marcia Lynx Qualey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/22/world/battle-to-retake-iraqi-city-looms-as-test-of-obamas-isis-strategy.html?_r=1&quot;&gt;Battle to Retake Iraqi City Looms as Test of Obama’s ISIS Strategy - Michael R. Gordon and Eric Schmitt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.democracynow.org/2015/2/26/who_is_bankrolling_the_islamic_state&quot;&gt;Democracy Now interview with Patrick Cockburn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/02/22/world/battle-to-retake-iraqi-city-looms-as-test-of-obamas-isis-strategy.html?_r=1&quot;&gt;The Islamic State Is Losing Iraq - John Simpson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/2015/02/daesh-cia-mossad-quds-force-150226052024592.html&quot;&gt;ISIL, CIA, Mossad, Quds Force, etc - Marwan Bishara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inherent curiosity, self-sought and entirely mysterious at times, often leads to uncomfortable revelations. On many occasions if the subject is worth thinking about it’s because there may be more to what you believe about a certain subject matter than your initial response would reveal. This, perhaps, is where curiosity comes from in a sense; a part of your mind that nags and prods at your conscience in order to bring to the surface something real and of value. I think this may be all the more important when we consider the sophistication of the media machine behind movements like ISIS. Manipulation works, and whether we like it or not we are all susceptible. All the more reason in my mind to struggle with offering genuine thoughts about what we should do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this was difficult. I have come to the uneasy conclusion that some form of military intervention, a policy I would normally resist vehemently, should be considered given the argument that while ‘taking on’ Al Qaeda was always a misnomer, ISIS is in large part a territorial army and as such could be defeated. The question isn’t one of ‘what good would come of western involvement but one of ‘what option is the less awful.’ Whether a militaristic response would come in the form of a broad multi-national coalition or whether the Iraqi national army is capable of defeating them with help, I don’t know. What I’m far surer about is that we are unlikely to see the same degree of public outcry against militarism, as was the case in 2003 before Western powers engaged in Iraq. I’m also aware that those who wanted to depose of Saddam in the lead up to that war made similar arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a sad, tragic and an galling opinion to have come to. This video upsets me deeply and it upsets me more that I’ve come to adopt a position where yet more destruction is an inevitable outcome. But I watch this video, aware of the context, the circumstance around it - knowing full well that ISIS would in the end get what they want: war. The small comfort I have is that it’s an opinion that was hard won and that my liberalism finds great strength in struggling with decisions that ought to be struggled with.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/isis-museum/&quot;&gt;Struggling with a personal response to ISIS&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on February 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fitting future-tech into an old world ]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/windows-future/" />
  <id>/windows-future</id>
  <published>2015-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting exercise to think of the future as a permeating loop. Where technology flows through every aspect of our lives. Commentators tend to claim similar things about the here and now. Strictly speaking however, this isn’t all that true. Technology commands a lot of our time but I think there may be a larger distinction to be made about living &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; technology verses living &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a technologically advanced world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m reminded of the Peter Theil quote about how smart devices, these amazing products that fit into our hands tend to distract us from looking up at an old world. This holds true for the cities we live in to the transport systems we use and the systems we depend on such as government and education. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is far, far less innovation happening in the places that don’t fit into the palm of your hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why, for me, videos like the one below become so compelling. It was made by Microsoft and it is being touted as their vision of a future where technology is infused into leisure, home and the workplace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I particularly enjoyed seeing interfaces that are designed to fit into what is, in essence, an ordinary day. This I think is the compelling challenge: how can we augment an old world while maintaining the inherent human touches that we feel comfortable within? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w-tFdreZB94&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/windows-future/&quot;&gt;Fitting future-tech into an old world &lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on February 26, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Henry Hobson made these throwback oscars graphics]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/oscars-graphics/" />
  <id>/oscars-graphics</id>
  <published>2015-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</published>
  <updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Guy Gunaratne</name>
    <uri></uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;While I stayed up for as long as I could on the night of the Oscars, my bleary eyes did catch sight of the quite beautiful graphics that were made for the Best Film title sequences. I particularly enjoyed the transitions made between each nomination. They were designed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.henryhobson.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Henry Hobson&lt;/a&gt; together with the animation studio &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elastic.tv/&quot;&gt;Elastic&lt;/a&gt;. The ones for Birdman and Whiplash had me remember those gorgeous old Hitchcock title sequences for Vertigo and North By Northwest. The latter is a personal favourite. I must remember to watch it again sometime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/120316233&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Today I also came across the site design for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dogstudio.be/&quot;&gt;Dogstudio&lt;/a&gt;. The ink-like transitions between pages are just as illustrative. For instance, try clicking through the nav bar.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/oscars-graphics/&quot;&gt;Henry Hobson made these throwback oscars graphics&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Guy Gunaratne at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Liberal Letters & Code&lt;/a&gt; on February 25, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
